Guide to the Burleith Garden Club records, 1949-2000 MS2023
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Burleith Garden Club records
1949-2000
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Burleith Garden Club (Washington, D.C.)
MS2023
1.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains bylaws, annual reports, membership lists, lists of officers, flyers, correspondence, one stapled booklet "My Favorite Recipes", and the neighborhood tot lot and flower mart generated by the Burleith Garden Club between 1949 and 2000.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
On September 25, 2002, Ms. Sara Revis donated archival papers from the Burleith Garden to The George Washington University Gelman Library.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Burleith Garden Club began on October 18, 1949 with fourteen members attending the first meeting. In 1950, the club decided to join the Burleith Citizens Association, but became independent again in 1954. The Burleith Garden Club is one of the charter members of the National Capital Garden Club League.
The Burleith Garden Club activities included speakers at the monthly meetings, and landscaping work in the community. For example, at one point, the club collected funds from homeowners to protect the Burleith community from Japanese beetles. The areas covered by the Japanese beetle program included private homes, parks, and school property. In addition, members participated in the flower show held at the National Guard Armory serving as judges, hostesses, and entrants. The club held garden tours in the spring and provided flowers and plants to shut-ins and the elderly during Christmas and Easter. At the April 2000 meeting, in response to declining membership, the club endorsed a proposal to become a standing committee of the Burleith Citizens Association.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains bylaws, annual reports, membership lists, lists of officers, flyers, correspondence, one stapled booklet "My Favorite Recipes", and the neighborhood tot lot and flower mart. The materials span the dates 1949-2000.
Collection Organization
Organized into three series: General files, Graphics, and Minutes.
Washington (D.C.); Landscape gardening; Flower shows; Burleith (Washington, D.C.); Burleith Citizens Association (Washington, D.C.); Burleith Garden Club (Washington, D.C.)
- General files, 1949-1998; MS2023 Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains annual reports, and membership dues that help relay the story of the operational workings of the club. This series consists of a sample of the type of issues and topics important to the garden club. This includes organizations they associated with such as the Friends of the National Arboretum. The material dates from 1949-98.
  - Annual Reports, 1956-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
  - Burleith Garden and Nature Club News, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - By-laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence of Burleith Garden Club, 1949-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between Sara Revis and District of Columbia Board of Trade, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between Charlotte Walker and Mrs. Gibson, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence letter to Peggy Concerning Flower Mart, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fairfax Bio Lab Sales, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fern Valley Trail Guide, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fillmore Arts Center, 1984-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Flea Market, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Friends of River Farm membership form, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Friends of the U.S. National Arboretum, 1960-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Garden Notes from Brookside Gardens, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Garden Resources of Washington, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - History of Burleith Garden Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Invitations, meeting invitations, 1957-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Johnson's Information Sheet, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Member lists, officer lists and past presidents, 1954-1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Membership dues, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - National Flower Week, 1957-1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - News articles and miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Newsletter, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Obituaries for members, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Personal notes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Plant Care, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Programs, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Recipe: Stephanie Brown's favorite, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Schedule, 1982-1992 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Stoddert Elementary School, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Tour, Garden, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Video Rental Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Washington National Cathedral Flower Mart 1992 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Workshops and announcements 1950-1997 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Graphics, undated; MS2023 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of photographs and slides. These images represent Garden Club activities such as the flower mart, Hillwood, and a picnic. Some of the images relate to the work the club did for the Burleith neighborhood such as landscaping for the tot lot.
  - Flower Mart photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Hillwood photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Jane Picnic photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - River Farm photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Tot Lot photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Unidentified slides, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Minutes, 1949-2000; MS2023 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of club minutes. The records run from the first meeting in 1949 until its last meeting in 2000 when the club decided to transition into a committee within the Burleith Citizens Association.
  - Minutes, 1949 November (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Member list and attendance list, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Minutes, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Minutes, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Minutes, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Minutes, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Minutes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Minutes, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Minutes, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Minutes, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Minutes, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Minutes, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Minutes, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Minutes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Minutes, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Minutes, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Minutes, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Treasurer's report, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Minutes, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 52)